Rajat Kumar Sahoo

IT Operation Support and Service | Agile | Scrum | Lean | Kanban

+91 8305186377 rajatkumarsahoonx@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajatkumarsahoo Raipur, IN

Summary

Experienced IT professionalwith over 17 years in Technology projects in IT. Focused on Implementation and Operation. Sucessfully Manages team, vendor, Implementation of IT infrastructure. On the way to transform carrer on Project Management help of agile methodologies using framework Scrum, Lean Six Sigma and Kanban.

Skills

Linux, Windows, HP-UX, IBM-AIX, VMware, HPe 3par, Vulunerability Remediation, Patching of Linux, Windows and VMware, Networking DNS, DHCP, Switch, IPv4, Subnetting, Backup IBM Spectrum Protect Plus, Hardware DELL and HPe, Cloud Azure and AWS, Shell Scripting, IAM, Active Directory Project Management, Scrum, Lean six sigma green Belt and Kanban, Team and Vendor mangement, Vendor Selection, SLA

Education

Pursuing-PGP Project Management iHUB IIT Roorkee by Simplilearn

MBA- (Project Leadership Management)

PGDITM- (IT& Management)

BITM- (Network Engineering)

Certifications

Redhat Certified System Administrator

Redhat Certified Engineer

Redhat Certified Openstack Administrator 6.0

hp Certified System Administrator

ITIL Foundation v3

VMware Certified Professional

Azure Fundamentals

Download Resume

https://github.com/rajatkumarsahoonx/my-Resume

Work Experience

Company- TATA Projects Ltd, Raipur- April 2018 - Present

Designation-Manager Role- Server Administrator

Tools- Linux, Windows, VMware, IBM SPP, hpe 3par, Zoho Patch Manager, Zoho Servicedesk, Hardware-hpe chassis, Balde, Dell, iLO, iDRAC, vCenter, Putty, Data Center.

Responsibility- In this Production Environment- From Implementation to Handover.

Windows & Linux virtual machine creation, LUN allocation and deletion, Patching of Hpe and Dell firmware and LINUX/Windows installation and patching. Resource allocation and OS trouble shooting, Actice Directory,NTP,File server, DNS,Log analysis, SLA, RCA submission,Vendor selection and management. Backup System creation and Manage. Palnning for developmental work execution. Vulnerability remediation. In datacenter implimentation Rack mount, Physical server mount and connection & Team Management

Company- Ca Technologies, HYD-May 2010- June 2017

Designation- Associate Platform Administrator Role- Infrastructure Support

Awards and Recognition - Above and Beyond Award Received Two times

Tools-Linux,Windows,HPUX,AIX,VMware,caServiceDesk,SSRM,LOD2.0,ServerAuto, Windows cluster, Private cloud,Putty, Data Center.

Our daily services, IaaS,PaaS,SaaS, Environment Test, Build, Production, POC. Linux, HP-UX/AIX, Windows, VMware, Private Cloud, Ticketing tool used Ca ServiceDesk, Lab Consolidation, V2V, P2V, LVM, RCA, Log Analysis, Installation, Performance tuning and troubleshooting,Resource allocation. POC before release of new OS/Cluster or new application, Patching of OS, firmware. New environment creation and placing them for production.Basic network issue resolution, Active Directory. Services offers to **Ca** Internal Global Customers from Hyderabad.

Company-NeCX India Pvt Ltd-June 2007- Apr 2010

Designation- FM Engineer Role- Support Server, Desktop and network

Facility Management Engineering Service- Replacement of Server and Desktop hardwares and Components, Co-Ordination between Wipro Management (IAS & Logistic team) and Client, L2 Networking. Support to Wipro Infotech's Customer at Hyderabad.

For Career Transformation Learning

Cloud - PMP - Scrum -Lean Six Sigma- Data Analytics

Project- Smart Weather Using **Jira** application on agile methodologies and framework **Scrum** by Simplilearn and iHUB_IIT Roorkee.

I hereby declare that all the above information is true and correct.

Rajat Kumar Sahoo